[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ad", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Argentina?", "answer": "Aconcagua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339edc", "question": "What position was first held by Caesar Augustus?", "answer": "Emperor of Rome", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b748364247bf200fb870", "question": "What is the atomic number for Hydrogen?", "answer": "1", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca74", "question": "How many feet is a fathom?", "answer": "6", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897a", "question": "In the book \"Animal Farm\", what boar originally encouraged the other animals to rebel against Farmer Jones?", "answer": "Old Major", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a12", "question": "What other actress plays around with Liv Tyler in Aerosmith\u2019s video for \"Crazy\"?", "answer": "Alicia Silverstone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe698cf20565ad31a57c73a", "question": "Who discovered Odysseus when he washed up on Phaeacia?", "answer": "Nausicaa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bc", "question": "What natural \"Wonder of the World\" lies off the east coast of Australia?", "answer": "The Great Barrier Reef", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59636d9b967692ea851899ae", "question": "The surface of what is typically 70% water and 10% ice?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a4", "question": "Natalie Coughlin won six medals in what sport at the 2008 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Swimming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b4", "question": "Anthony Robert McMillan is more famous as who?", "answer": "Robbie Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3625ff048f679a45ab09", "question": "Which mammal has no vocal cords?", "answer": "Giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea7fc5ff048f679a45ac15", "question": "What is the lightest element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b077", "question": "What was the last name of Civil Rights activist Malcolm X?", "answer": "Little", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a371", "question": "Where is the Darjeeling tea grown?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab963a86faa38a764be51d", "question": "What was the original cost of the first Ford Model T, sold in 1909?", "answer": "$825", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594fb9a8210241017090b57e", "question": "What year did the interval act \"Riverdance\" debut at the Eurovision Song Contest?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfb8a5003d27d341092bbf", "question": "What is the lowest elevation point in the Western Hemisphere?", "answer": "Laguna del Carbon, Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb7", "question": "Which American statistician founded the institute of Public Opinion in 1935?", "answer": "Gallup", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937eee908d98002fdd633da", "question": "What is 2000 in Roman Numerals?", "answer": "MM", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b60e", "question": "What Kimberly-Clark product was advertised as having a snug elastic fit and an hourglass shape?", "answer": "Huggies diapers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7358ceec85e375820b24d", "question": "Who said, \"Success is the ability to go from one failure to another with no loss of enthusiasm.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a68c", "question": "What river flows along the western boundary of New Jersey?", "answer": "Delaware River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b07f", "question": "How many electoral votes did Gerald Ford get in the \u201976 election?", "answer": "240", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a2", "question": "What year did the iPhone debut on the market?", "answer": "2007", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0d", "question": "What are the two fruit juices in a cosmopolitan?", "answer": "Cranberry and lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9bbe5364247bf200fb8aa", "question": "What country borders Zambia to the west?", "answer": "Angola", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a803", "question": "What city is overlooked by a large statue named \"Christ the Redeemer\"?", "answer": "Rio de Janeiro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac8", "question": "The folklore characters known as \"oni\" originated in which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fc", "question": "Who got to No. 3 in the UK with the song \"Joe Le Taxi\"?", "answer": "Vanessa Paradis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b4", "question": "Canadian Prime Minister Lester Pearson won the Nobel Peace Prize for defusing what world crisis?", "answer": "The Suez Crisis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121d2863c99d48cd169b1b", "question": "The \"Maman\" sculpture in Bilbao, Spain is a giant what?", "answer": "Spider - The huge arachnid is modeled after the artist Louise Bourgeois\u2019s mother. It was her representation of her weaver mother.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb23", "question": "What NFL team did the Denver Broncos defeat to win their second Super Bowl?", "answer": "Atlanta Falcons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a659", "question": "Which eastern US state is home to the Kittatinny Mountains?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecdad4ec223966ae8f88ec", "question": "In what movie did Sidney Poitier say, \"They call me Mister Tibbs\"?", "answer": "\"In the Heat of the Night\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b0e86c964118b2bb3809c5", "question": "In Slovenia, Saint Valentine is considered the saint of good health and the patron of whom?", "answer": "Beekeepers and pilgrims", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa56", "question": "What is the capital of the Canadian Province of Quebec?", "answer": "Quebec City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4b7d106d333868d34d6fa", "question": "What was the name of the anti-Castro group at the \"Bay of Pigs\"?", "answer": "La Brigada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600242964be4723ccac22189", "question": "Which novel was first published in October 1847 under the pen name \"Currer Bell\"?", "answer": "\"Jane Eyre\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b238", "question": "Harry Truman was the first US president of what religious persuasion?", "answer": "Southern Baptist", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9bbba364247bf200fb8a6", "question": "What is the capital of Zambia?", "answer": "Lusaka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5971e13a89261e916c8e09b2", "question": "What alien species is affected by the Genophage in the Mass Effect Series?", "answer": "Krogan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b378", "question": "What was the nationality of Franz Liszt?", "answer": "Hungarian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4de3306d333868d34d710", "question": "What name is given to Britain\u2019s policy of avoiding strict enforcement of parliamentary laws on early American colonies?", "answer": "Salutary neglect", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8b", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"A Place in the Sun\" based on?", "answer": "An American Tragedy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9b", "question": "What movie did the villain Harry Powell appear in?", "answer": "The Night of the Hunter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9a84ebfabb9c85d8a97c", "question": "Which mythical creature has the body of a lion, a goat's head rising from its back and a snake's head at the tip of its tail?", "answer": "Chimaera, or Chimera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af25961b63e5727cf5a484d", "question": "Celine Dion's \"My Heart Will Go On\" song was featured as the main theme song to which 1990's movie?", "answer": "Titanic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d2", "question": "What was Murray Langston better known as to the public?", "answer": "The Unknown Comic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbe9", "question": "What is known as the \"white pearl of India\"?", "answer": "The Taj Mahal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b549", "question": "What is \"hotel-Dieu\" in France?", "answer": "A hospital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec881aec223966ae8f881b", "question": "Blondie of the film \"The Good, the Bad and the Ugly\" is also known by what name?", "answer": "\"the Man with No Name\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b61a", "question": "Which company introduced Comet cleanser back in 1956?", "answer": "Procter & Gamble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff213c431a458464a93c452", "question": "A \"hot dog\" is a colloquial term used for what food?", "answer": "Frankfurter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acfb", "question": "Which famous family owned a cat named Socks?", "answer": "The Clintons", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af27", "question": "Which European country ruled the Philippine Islands as a colony before 1898?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b967", "question": "How many ballet dancers would you find dancing a \u2018pas de deux\u2019?", "answer": "2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f5efff048f679a45aad9", "question": "What physicist discovered that a wave's frequency changes when the source and the observer are in motion relative to one another?", "answer": "Christian Doppler", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be69", "question": "What is Lambeau Field's nickname?", "answer": "The Frozen Tundra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5901dd46709c1c34536e6eb8", "question": "What rock band were David Gilmour, Roger Waters, Richard Wright and Nick Mason in?", "answer": "Pink Floyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde4f37c6c6b019850c9a89", "question": "The Huguenots in France had their rights taken away by the revocation of what document?", "answer": "Edict Of Nantes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9d", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Bombadil?", "answer": "J.R.R. Tolkien", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a200", "question": "Who was the very first actor to win two consecutive Best Actor Oscars?", "answer": "Spencer Tracy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e986bebfabb9c85d8a96b", "question": "Who released the album \"Tuesday Night Music Club\" in 1993?", "answer": "Sheryl Crow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feccb2eec223966ae8f889d", "question": "What 1987 movie features the \"Partridge Family\" house being firebombed?", "answer": "\"Lethal Weapon\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e9a", "question": "Who gave Impressionism its name with his 1873 painting \"Impression, Sunrise\"?", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa9", "question": "Who wrote The Angel Doll: A Christmas Story in 1996?", "answer": "Jerry Bledsoe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6991c20565ad31a57c741", "question": "What is the name of the Miami Heat mascot?", "answer": "Burnie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6e5", "question": "What French scientist discovered that many diseases are caused by germs?", "answer": "Louis Pasteur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b169", "question": "What was the name of the site used to build the Empire State Building?", "answer": "John Thompson Farm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ea", "question": "In the 1991 movie \"Thelma and Louise\" who plays the part of Louise?", "answer": "Susan Sarandon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c329", "question": "What characteristic of light allows it to be separated into a spectrum of color?", "answer": "Wavelength", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e147934dd42e4a67cb8d3ed", "question": "Who painted the famous work of art known as \"The Death of Socrates\"?", "answer": "Jacques-Louis David", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339147", "question": "What year did Pinocchio first appear in published media?", "answer": "1883", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d61", "question": "Who wrote the 1963 novel \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Pierre Boulle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b022", "question": "What world leader was Time magazine's \"Man of the Year\" for 1938?", "answer": "Adolf Hitler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4bb", "question": "Anthracite and bituminous are two types of what mineral?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa66", "question": "What is the capital of Kuwait?", "answer": "Kuwait City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc8560fabc30a8194e188af", "question": "In which three films did Bill Paxton and Michael Bien both have roles?", "answer": "\"Terminator\", \"Aliens\" and \"Tombstone\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "595642f2803c1f1ebcc4a02e", "question": "Who took home the Academy of Country Music\u2019s Male Vocalist trophy every year between 2006 and 2010?", "answer": "Brad Paisley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c028d55ea32143fcb1d3b58", "question": "In which state is Walla Walla County located?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b4", "question": "What is the name of the reverend who appears in the cartoon series \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Timothy Lovejoy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b7", "question": "What nationality is actor Stephen Fry?", "answer": "British", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3e", "question": "What board game's tokens include a rope, a lead pipe, and a candlestick?", "answer": "Clue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a90", "question": "Who provides James Bond with his gadgets?", "answer": "Q", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e776fe83fe1f2a824bd3", "question": "What were the names of the five beachhead at Normandy on D-Day?", "answer": "Utah, Omaha, Gold, Juno, and Sword", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c544fbde8045e48466aa", "question": "What is the dugong's (sea cow) closest land relative?", "answer": "Elephant \u2010- Like elephants, males can grow tusks when they reach maturity.  Females can grow tusks, too, if they live long enough.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded12cea2747c8aff16d30", "question": "Who was kidnapped on the night of March 1, 1932?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4bef49076251badbeaca", "question": "Which U.S. President had his sister initially serve as First Lady?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland -- \u00a0His sister Rose Cleveland took on the duties of First Lady until he married his bride Frances in June 1886.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c485", "question": "What is the name of the point of no return around the edge of a black hole?", "answer": "Event horizon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff3c2f64f032c0db195b488", "question": "What charter did a group of English barons force King John to sign in 1215 at Runnymede?", "answer": "Magna Carta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6013711e1381754895396389", "question": "Who was the original host of \"Wheel of Fortune\"?", "answer": "The original host was Chuck Woolery, a game show mainstay who left the show in 1981 over contract disputes.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c5049076251badbead1", "question": "The term \"first family\" came into popularity under which U.S. President?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy -- Comedian/Kennedy impressionist Vaughn Meader titled his Grammy-winning 1962 album \"First Family\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e46", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"The Scorpion King\"?", "answer": "The Rock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede5b66ce05a3942286def", "question": "Which American television sitcom is about a witch who marries an ordinary man and lives as a suburban housewife?", "answer": "\"Bewitched\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ca", "question": "What San Francisco hill is home to a famous colony of wild parrots?", "answer": "Telegraph Hill", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f14", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Willem Defoe and James Caviezel?", "answer": "Jesus Christ", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b345", "question": "In what year did Captain Cook reach New Zealand?", "answer": "1769", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5907229d3745b36be7303a01", "question": "The nearest permanently inhabited place to the North Pole is part of which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c3b49076251badbead0", "question": "Which First Lady was the first to graduate college?", "answer": "Lucy Hayes -- The wife of President Rutherford B. Hayes, she received her degree from Wesleyan Female College at the age of 18.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b717", "question": "What song's lyrics include \"tap, tap, tapping at your windowpane and bringing joy to every girl and boy\"?", "answer": "Suzy Snowflake", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca89", "question": "What element that is lacking in a diet causes goitre?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa86a6ce05a3942286ed0", "question": "Who was originally to be cast as Axel Foley in the film \"Beverly Hills Cop\"?", "answer": "Sylvester Stallone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a630", "question": "What river defines the southern border of Oklahoma?", "answer": "Red River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72c", "question": "What desert is located just north of the Sonoran Desert?", "answer": "Mojave Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad27", "question": "What Undersecretary of the United Nations became the first African-American to win the Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "Ralph Bunche", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc9", "question": "What can a lycanthrope do ?", "answer": "Change into a wolf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a5", "question": "What car lost 96 percent of its sales in the four years after the publication of Ralph Nader's \"Unsafe at Any Speed\"?", "answer": "Chevrolet Corvair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922e", "question": "Who stars in the semi-autobiographical movie \"Purple Rain\"?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a2", "question": "How many sides does a nonagon have?", "answer": "9", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fde4f72c6c6b019850c9a8a", "question": "Who is credited with being the first Pharaoh of Egypt?", "answer": "Menes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e8", "question": "In what city is Jim Morrison buried?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133983c", "question": "What music awards were founded in 1958?", "answer": "The Grammy Awards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339486", "question": "In what US city does Hitchcock's movie \"Vertigo\" take place?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93d86ce05a3942286e92", "question": "When did Spanish golf legend Seve Ballesteros win his first Masters Tournament?", "answer": "1980 at the age of 23", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927c", "question": "What are the only 100% guarantees of safety in the TV show \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Head of Household and Veto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c100", "question": "What three letter word stands for a small opening and a clothing company?", "answer": "Gap", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ce", "question": "Who directed the film \"Ordinary People\"?", "answer": "Robert Redford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d9", "question": "What number does the roman numeral LXXX denote?", "answer": "80", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b668", "question": "What is the length-to-width ratio of a regulation pool table?", "answer": "2:1", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c736", "question": "What alloy is comprised of copper and zinc?", "answer": "Brass", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec87eaec223966ae8f8819", "question": "Which Country won the Fed Cup consecutively, between 1976 and 1982?", "answer": "USA", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffe4c5047818f5674af01b6", "question": "How did Robert Frost sum up everything he learned about life?", "answer": "\"It goes on.\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe73503eec85e375820b241", "question": "On two separate occasions, President Ford was shot at by which two people?", "answer": "Lynette \"Squeaky\" Fromme and Sara Jane Moore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3c0704f032c0db195b476", "question": "Before he escaped and returned to France, Napoleon had been exiled to what island in 1814?", "answer": "Elba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8cb", "question": "Luteinizing hormone is produced by what gland in the human body?", "answer": "Pituitary", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd662f0a5bfecdd737e084a", "question": "Who was the first woman to become U.S. Secretary of State?", "answer": "Madeline Albright", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff66b3a52a821ff76ae8b0d", "question": "Which Old West figure became sports editor for the \"New York Morning Telegraph\"?", "answer": "William Barclay \"Bat\" Masterson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7eb8eb24f84e0b9f9ffde", "question": "What state borders Alabama to the north?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce1", "question": "What term for elaborate, decorative lettering comes from the Greek meaning \"beautiful writing\"?", "answer": "Calligraphy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea78c8ff048f679a45abdd", "question": "Gray, blue, bowhead and finback are varieties of what?", "answer": "Whales", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8df", "question": "What popular tourist destination is Thailand's largest island?", "answer": "Phuket", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae95", "question": "Where did Davy Crockett die?", "answer": "The Alamo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e2fd06d333868d34d72b", "question": "Which conflict ended with the \"Good Friday Agreement\"?", "answer": "The Troubles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9bb7d364247bf200fb8a4", "question": "Which UK group won the 1981 Eurovision Song Contest?", "answer": "Bucks Fizz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b5a0e662d71a53650ffd", "question": "How did Jay Gatsby make his money in \"The Great Gatsby\"?", "answer": "Bootlegging", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3c", "question": "Which element appears eighth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c3721815febcc896f926d", "question": "What is a group of mallards in flight called?", "answer": "A Sord", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff4", "question": "What 1968 film takes place partially in the Sea of Holes?", "answer": "Yellow Submarine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feccccfec223966ae8f88a5", "question": "In \"Big Hero 6\", what did the animators model Baymax's movements after?", "answer": "A baby with a full diaper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf8b", "question": "What's the main feature of a Chong Sang skirt?", "answer": "Split up side", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08d", "question": "Who hosted the 1997 Grammy Awards?", "answer": "Ellen Degeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc1bb6de0eb824d4052e2", "question": "What Islands make up the U.S. Virgin Islands?", "answer": "The U.S. Virgin Islands consist of Saint Croix, Saint Thomas, Saint John, and Water Island, alongside 50 other tiny islets.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a221", "question": "Who played Beau Geste in the 1939 film by the same name?", "answer": "Gary Cooper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af28", "question": "Who founded the city of Singapore?", "answer": "Stamford Raffles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59c1cde77bd84c0ea43ad431", "question": "In Norse mythology, what did Odin trade an eye for?", "answer": "Wisdom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a00d6c0f9723ab15cb32", "question": "What year was the first black hole discovered?", "answer": "1971", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd4", "question": "Baklava is usually made using what kind of paper-thin dough?", "answer": "Filo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a551b63e1c6f9840ba318e", "question": "Which country owns the island of Corfu?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5cfe6ce05a3942286e28", "question": "Which iconic \u201880s role required training from a professional mime?", "answer": "\"Robocop\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d9", "question": "In what year were the two James Bond films \"Octopussy\" and \"Never Say Never Again\" released?", "answer": "1983", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a332", "question": "What was the name of Ross' pet monkey on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Marcell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe12f35e39efa6330e0fed7", "question": "Where is the world's shortest commercial runway?", "answer": "Saba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d51", "question": "Author Margaret Atwood is a graduate of which Canadian University?", "answer": "University of Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa39", "question": "Which continent would you find the Amur River in?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede6216ce05a3942286df6", "question": "Who is the host of the Travel Channel's culinary adventure show \"No Reservations\"?", "answer": "Anthony Bourdain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfb4d9dc5ec6cd98a8316", "question": "What painting by Andrew Wyeth depicts a woman lying on the ground?", "answer": "\"Christina's World\"\u00a0-- It depicts a woman lying on the ground in a mostly tawny field, looking up at a gray house on the horizon.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f166daf7c52aae91cc07b3", "question": "Which drug, later found to have devastating side effects, was launched in 1957 to help pregnant women overcome morning sickness?", "answer": "Thalidomide", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b328", "question": "What state did Harry Truman represent as a US Senator before becoming President of the Unites States?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b676", "question": "What does B stand for when referring to a camera's shutter speed?", "answer": "Bulb", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338941", "question": "What creatures in \"The Lord of the Rings\" are referred to as goblins in the book \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "Orcs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e7", "question": "What singer first hit #1 in 1984 with \"Caribbean Queen (No More Love on the Run)\"?", "answer": "Billy Ocean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b5a", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Tarzan of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Edgar Rice Burroughs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb25", "question": "In the book of Genesis, what is said to measure 300 by 50 by 30 cubits?", "answer": "Noah's Ark", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa7", "question": "What Saturday Evening Post artist was known for his whimsical pictures of Santa Claus?", "answer": "Norman Rockwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3818ff048f679a45ab21", "question": "What is a unit that measures force?", "answer": "Newtons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c477", "question": "What is cryogenics the study of?", "answer": "Production of low temperatures", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a8", "question": "In the movie \"Rebel Without A Cause\", who dies in the chicky race?", "answer": "Buzz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2b", "question": "What is the capital of Fiji?", "answer": "Suva", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338985", "question": "What is the only nationality mentioned in the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\"?", "answer": "French", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a3d920565ad31a57c7b8", "question": "Who was the first American woman to win the Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "Jane Addams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc5086ce05a3942286f3a", "question": "What kind of gun does Harry Callahan use to kill Mick in the film \"Sudden Impact\"?", "answer": ".44 AMP Auto Mag Model 180", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8b", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Aliaune Thiam?", "answer": "Akon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c5", "question": "Who had a No.1 hit song in 1998 with \"C'est la Vie\"?", "answer": "B*Witched", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397da", "question": "What did Marilyn Monroe claim was the only thing she wore in bed?", "answer": "Chanel No. 5", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c76e877e98cb977789ce", "question": "Which continent is home to the only egg-laying mammals in the world?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c43e", "question": "What name is given to someone who keeps \"apis mellifera\"?", "answer": "Beekeeper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c418", "question": "What name is given to the closest star to the Earth?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c028cf8ea32143fcb1d3b54", "question": "What does a chromophobe fear?", "answer": "Colors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ddd", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"pundit\"?", "answer": "Hindi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d6e92596a59cbdfbd3af", "question": "What was Henry Ford\u2019s original design for a car called?", "answer": "Quadricycle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa387cc73aa70ea0b70ad1", "question": "What does Texas\u2019 original name mean?", "answer": "Friends", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65d8f1f3c0ead6880d61d", "question": "In World War II, what type of airplane did Marine ace Pappy Boyington fly?", "answer": "F4U Corsair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a899c3c60d398dc9cf7a6a6", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek goddess Hestia?", "answer": "Vesta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a0", "question": "Who was the star of the 1928 movie \"Steamboat Willie\"?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfe00fcb668d7dfe168b5c7", "question": "When did Napoleon Bonaparte begin his reign as Emperor of the French?", "answer": "1804", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d08241a1c922dd1ac64c0", "question": "Ulaanbaatar is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Mongolia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "596761082b59efe0e9417ea0", "question": "The fear of some unknown evil is called what?", "answer": "Panphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe766c3eec85e375820b289", "question": "What capital city is the only one located on the equator?", "answer": "Quito, Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a32c", "question": "What year was the film \"48 Hrs.\", starring Eddie Murphy and Nick Nolte released?", "answer": "1982", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6f", "question": "Who draft-dodged the Trojan War by dressing as a woman in the court of King Lycomedes?", "answer": "Achillies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b410", "question": "What Shakespearean king was actually king of Scotland for 17 years?", "answer": "Macbeth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd9701f23c87fd04dd15e46", "question": "Which President banned Christmas trees from the White House?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c183", "question": "What food item literally means \"twice-cooked\"?", "answer": "Biscuit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97c", "question": "In the bible Zacharias and Elizabeth were the parents of whom?", "answer": "John The Baptist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078c3d0eee65b76b9f2670", "question": "Britain\u2019s Bantam Battalions were composed of what kind of soldiers?", "answer": "Undersized (The British created a battalion for undersized volunteers, nicknamed the Bantams - a type of small, ferocious bird.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e12", "question": "What two \"Brokeback Mountain\" actors have siblings who are also award-winning actors?", "answer": "Jake Gyllenhaal and Randy Quaid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab75", "question": "What is the capital of Mauritius?", "answer": "Port Louis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c728", "question": "Who was the first man to return safely from space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5989ad56cb8751d53e7d7610", "question": "What name is shared by an 1849 painting by Asher Durand, and a sculpture situated in Bailick Park in Midleton, Ireland?", "answer": "Kindred Spirits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133badc", "question": "A person described as a \"towhead\" has what color hair?", "answer": "Blonde", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc0c66de0eb824d4052db", "question": "In which mountain range can you find Australia\u2019s tallest peak?", "answer": "Australian Alps -- It is covered in ski resorts and in the summer, many people hike to its tallest peak, Mount Kosciuszko.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7351ceec85e375820b244", "question": "Who was Dwight D. Eisenhower's vice president?", "answer": "Richard M. Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c0", "question": "What category of writing are the Hugo and Nebula awards given for?", "answer": "Science Fiction", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a51", "question": "In the novel \"Mrs. Mike\", the young Boston girl married a sergeant in what?", "answer": "The Royal Canadian Mounted Police", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb60d05dad637d903c882c", "question": "The Rungnado 1st of May Stadium, built in honor of the May Day holiday, exists in which country?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339528", "question": "Who directed the 1990 movie \"La Femme Nikita\"?", "answer": "Luc Besson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f30bcee580c7f8fd1e54", "question": "Who said, \"I only regret that I have but only one life to lose for my country.\"?", "answer": "Nathan Hale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a1", "question": "The Broadway show \"Movin' Out\" was based on songs written by what singing star?", "answer": "Billy Joel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf59", "question": "Who wrote the mIRC chat software?", "answer": "Khaled Mardam-Bey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b614", "question": "First marketed in 1952, Pream was a brand of instant what?", "answer": "Creamer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f16accf7c52aae91cc07e1", "question": "Which state is home to Australia's highest mainland mountain?", "answer": "New South Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b804", "question": "In a Scrabble game, what is the term for using all seven letters in one turn?", "answer": "Bingo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f5674f33a95c66dc4fe769", "question": "Who is Mega Man's creator?", "answer": "Dr. Light", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae9", "question": "The second video ever played on MTV was by what female artist?", "answer": "Pat Benatar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd9", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Merchant of Venice\", who was Shylocks wife?", "answer": "Leah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c255", "question": "What does a barometer measure?", "answer": "Atmospheric Pressure", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffcfd749dc5ec6cd98a8324", "question": "What famous literary character offers this sage advice: \"Neither a borrower nor a lender be\"?", "answer": "Polonius (In\u00a0\"Hamlet\"\u00a0(Act I, Scene III),\u00a0he offers the sage advice to his son Laertes who is about to leave home.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a745", "question": "Which is the fourth largest US state in surface area?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b50201dd7bf43be5e7cb", "question": "What is the main ingredient in the British dish laverbread?", "answer": "Seaweed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b484", "question": "What year was actor Arthur Stanley Jefferson born?", "answer": "1890", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5db03eddaa1c9af2684d79a5", "question": "In the classic fighting game series \"Street Fighter\", what does the move \"Shoryuken\" mean in Japanese?", "answer": "Rising Dragon Punch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3589855db0d66a186cb54c", "question": "The Republic of Benin shares a border with which other African country to the east?", "answer": "Nigeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6bb", "question": "Mariner 9 was the first spacecraft to orbit what other planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c369", "question": "What was the hottest part of \"Concorde\" in flight after the engines?", "answer": "Nose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339241", "question": "Who are Bart Simpson's favorite cartoon duo?", "answer": "Itchy and Scratchy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feccdefec223966ae8f88ae", "question": "In which movie did 007 first utter the iconic phrase: \"Bond ... James Bond\"?", "answer": "\"Dr. No\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029fe7cad1ec93f27df765", "question": "What country does the cappuccino originate from?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ca", "question": "What is a young bee fed to develop into a queen?", "answer": "Royal jelly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f3f901dd7bf43be5e81c", "question": "UNICEF stands for what?", "answer": "The United Nations International Children's Emergency Fund", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf02", "question": "What animal is the mascot of the US Naval Academy?", "answer": "The goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab97d086faa38a764be52b", "question": "What was the nickname of the Ford Mustang featured in the 1974 film \"Gone in 60 Seconds\"?", "answer": "Eleanor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98a", "question": "Which former heavyweight champion was nicknamed the \"Brockton blockbuster\"?", "answer": "Rocky Marciano", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1e5", "question": "Which US president lived in Montpelier?", "answer": "James Madison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a619", "question": "The Makah Indians lived on which coast?", "answer": "West coast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339209", "question": "What is the four-letter name of the groundhog in Groundhog Day?", "answer": "Phil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ea", "question": "What singer began his career fronting the bands of Harry James and Tommy Dorsey in the 1930\u2019s?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a396", "question": "What is the official language of Papua New Guinea?", "answer": "English", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bcc", "question": "What is the name of Boy George's 1982 debut album?", "answer": "Kissing to be Clever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7c1d22b316f4693fb679e", "question": "What is eaten traditionally in the UK the day before Ash Wednesday?", "answer": "Pancakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beae", "question": "Who wears the \"Pescatorio\", or Ring of the Fisherman?", "answer": "The pope", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c545", "question": "In which part of the body are your metatarsals located?", "answer": "Foot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a67", "question": "Who wrote the children's book \"The Trumpet of the Swan\"?", "answer": "E.B. White", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60121cc563c99d48cd169b18", "question": "What is the real name of Chicago\u2019s \"The Bean\"?", "answer": "\"Cloud Gate\", by artist Sir Anish Kapoor, gives a perfect view of the Chicago skyline in its reflective stainless steel surface.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d9", "question": "What is a somnambulist?", "answer": "Sleepwalker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a899d9d60d398dc9cf7a6ad", "question": "What US Secretary of State received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973?", "answer": "Henry Kissinger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b3731c1c3f17ccc40c8e2a", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion in search of?", "answer": "Courage", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5fd96e1c23c87fd04dd15e33", "question": "What sport was Abraham Lincoln a champion in?", "answer": "Wrestling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf16", "question": "What's the seventh sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Libra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa5850c73aa70ea0b70b3b", "question": "What is the oldest state park in the United States?", "answer": "Although Yellowstone is America's oldest national park, New York\u2019s Niagara Falls State Park was the first state park.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb56", "question": "What brand of whisky was created in 1939 Queen of England's visit to Canada?", "answer": "Crown Royal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ca", "question": "The \"Dreamcatcher\" was invented by which Native America group?", "answer": "Ojibwe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af31", "question": "What organisation was given the only Nobel peace prize awarded during World War I?", "answer": "International Red Cross", "category": "history"}]